Ciupei Calin



calinciupei@gmail.com



https://www.calinciupei.com/

Summary

Experienced 8+ years Senior Frontend Developer with a demonstrated history of working in different types of industry like entertainment, tourism, and commerce. During my working experience as a Front-end Developer, I have improved my proficiency with JS, CSS, and HTML. Notable achievements include boosting the conversion rate of an existing SPA by 80% with improved code design.

Experience



Senior Frontend Developer

Paddy Power Betfair

Jan 2020 - Present (2 years 4 months +)

Migrated a multi-page component into a single-page app using Typescript, React, Redux, Redux-Saga, improving customer engagement.

Improve and deliver new features in multiple components using tools like React, Typescript, and AngularJs.

Performed code reviews and bug fixes, reducing technical debt.

Deliver multiple dynamic and browser compatible pages using HTML, CSS, Javascript (React, Redux, Redux-Saga, Typescript)

Built extensive test coverage for all new features, reducing the number of customer complaints.

Mentor and trained junior front end developers

Freelance Web Developer

You Are Smart Community

Mar 2021 - Present (1 year 2 months +)

Migrated a multi-page component into a single-page app using Typescript, React, Redux, Redux-Saga, improving customer engagement.

Improve and deliver new features in multiple components using tools like React, Typescript, and AngularJs.

Performed code reviews and bug fixes, reducing technical debt.

Deliver multiple dynamic and browser compatible pages using HTML, CSS, Javascript (React, Redux, Redux-Saga, Typescript)

Built extensive test coverage for all new features, reducing the number of customer complaints.

Mentor and trained junior front end developers

Front End Developer

Paddy Power Betfair

Jun 2016 - Jan 2020 (3 years 8 months)

Migrated a multi-page component into a single-page app using Angular Js, Angular improving customer engagement.

Improve and deliver new features in multiple components using frameworks like YUI, React, and AngularJs.

Migrate multiple components to styling code by using methodologies like CSS BEM and OOCSS Deliver multiple dynamic and browser compatible pages using HTML, CSS, Javascript (YUI, React, Redux)

Web Developer

IN2ITIVE

Jul 2015 - Jun 2016 (1 year)

Coordination, analysis and tasks estimation received from customers.

Develope and implement applications according to the requirements and standards.

Analyse code and propose solutions to achieve maximum performance by the team.

Provide support to clients from initial client interaction and requirements analysis through design, coding, testing, debugging, implementation.

Webmaster

Cognizant Softvision

Oct 2014 - Jul 2015 (10 months)

Take an active role in the full development life-cycle.

Successfully build and maintain a variety of applications and produce documentation and reports.

Testing, identifying problems, report them using Jira as Project Management Tool.

Providing first level technical support.

Web Developer

Freelance PHP & Python & Node.is developers

Oct 2012 - Oct 2014 (2 years 1 month)

Maintaining and enhancing company software.

Maintaining web components and websites for both new and existing clients.

Testing site functionality, identifying problems or bugs and fixing errors.

Coding using front-end technologies, such as CSS, JavaScript and HTML.

Ensure site usability, SEO and browser compatibility.

Working on back-end technologies such as PHP using Aptana Studio 3 as integrated development environment.

Involved in front-end design, site maintenance & email marketing campaigns.

Junior Test Engineer

Neusoft EDC

Dec 2011 - Aug 2012 (9 months)

Identification and reporting the bugs in bug tracking system;

Directing software compatibility tests with programs, hardware, operating systems, or network environments.

Functional testing of mobile applications on Windows platform.

Running test cases.

Reporting the found bugs.

Education

Technical University of Cluj Napoca

Master Of Computer Science, Master 2012 - 2014



Tehnical University of Cluj Napoca - Romania

Faculty of Electrical Engineering, Licensed 2004 - 2009 Computer Science

Skills

Front-End Development • JavaScript • React.js • Web Development • Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) • angular • AngularJS • Node.js • GraphQL • jQuery